Well, and let's also test that it returns false. If raffle isn't open.
嗯，让我们继续测试 `it("returns false if raffle isn't open")
This will be an async function.
这里是一个 `async function`
And we'll do everything except and we'll do everything in here. But we'll make the raffle in the calculating state.
我们就在这里处理所有内容，不过我们会先让抽奖处于 "CALCULATING" 状态
So do a weight, raffle dot enter, raffle value, raffle entrance fee
所以执行 `await raffle.enterRaffle()`
await network dot provider that send
`await network.provider.send()`
and I'm just going to copy these two lines here.
然后我要复制这两行
Because we're going to go ahead and do those.
因为我们下面就是要执行这些内容
We're also going to do a weight, raffle dot perform upkeep.
我们还要执行 `await raffle.performUpkeep`
And another way to send a blank bytes object is to do a string like 0x
另一种发送空字节对象的方式是写一个字符串 "0x"
hardhat is smart enough to know that this should be transformed into just kind of a blank bytes object.
hardhat 足够智能，它会把这个东西转换为一个空字节对象
So either one of these should work.
这两种方式中的任何一个都是可以的
Now we're do const, raffle state equals await, raffle dot get raffle state
现在我们执行 `const raffleState = await raffle.getRaffleState`
and we'll Get upkeep needed.
接下来我们要获取 "upkeepNeeded"
So we'll say const. upkeep needed,
所以我们要执行 `const `
we'll do exactly what we did above raffle dot call static dot check upkeep.
然后就和我们上面做的一样 `raffle.callStatic.checkUpkeep`
Let's say excuse me a weight, raffle dot call static.
抱歉，应该是 `await raffle.callStatic`
Now we can do assert dot equal, say raffle state is going to be, or excuse me raffle state.to string,
现在我们就可以执行 `assert.equal(raffleState.toString)
it's going to be calculating,
它应该为“计算中”
and I started dot equal upkeep needed, it's going to be false.
接下来是 `assert.equal(upkeepNeeded, false)`
Let's run a GREP on that.
让我们运行一下 `grep`
And perfect. That's also working correctly.
完美，同样运行正常
Great. Now I'm going to skip over these next two tests,
好的，现在我们要跳过接下来的两个测试
because we haven't really learned anything from them.
因为我们还没有了解过它们
So I'm just going to copy paste them from the GitHub,
我会直接从 GitHub 上把它们复制粘贴过来
we're going to return false if enough time hasn't passed.
它们是 `returns false if enough time hasn't passed`
(如果时间还没达到要求就返回 false)
And we're going to return true. If enough time has passed, we have players Eve and is open.
以及 `returns true if enough time has passed, has players, eth, and is open`
(如果时间达到要求且有玩家，有以太币，而且状态为打开则返回 true)
So we're just asserting true down here. And we're starting not true up here,
所以下面这里是 `assert(true)` 而上面则是 `assert(!true)`
you want to pause the video and copy paste these and write these out, you absolutely can
你可以先暂停视频，照着这里的内容写一遍
copy paste them from the GitHub repo, you absolutely can't like I said,
也可以从 GitHub 仓库中复制粘贴
going through this and making yourself write these and making yourself understand these tests is going to make you a substantially better coder.
就像我说的，仔细编写并理解这些测试会让你成为一个更好的程序员
And let's just test that it all looks good with hh test.
让我们测试一下，看看它是否正常 `hh test`
Now, as I was recording this, I just realized that for all of our describe blocks, I've been making them async functions
在我录现在这个视频的时候，我突然意识到，我们所有的 "describe" 用的都是 "async" 函数
describe blocks actually don't realize and can't recognize and can't work with promises.
"describe" 里其实是不能实现，也不能识别和处理 "promise" 的
So having the be async actually doesn't do anything.
所以把它们声明为 "async" 实际上并没有任何作用
So in your describe block, we want to get rid of the async word because it's actually not helping us at all.
所以我们要把 "describe" 中的 "async" 都去掉，因为它对我们来说没有任何作用
In fact, it's just an extra word, and it looks kind of gross.
事实上，它就是一个多余的词，只会让人看着很烦
So now all of our describe blocks, we're gonna get rid of that async keyword,
所以我们要把所有 "describe" 里的 "async" 关键字都去掉
and just have them be functions.
并把它们直接设置成 "function"
Of course, all of our it's, though, are going to be using asynchronous functions, which is what we want.
当然，对于所有的 "it" 来说，还是要使用异步函数，这是必要的
So we've written some tests for a checkup keep. Now let's go ahead to perform upkeep.
我们已经写了不少 "checkUpkeep" 的测试，现在该轮到 "performUpkeep" 了
Let's create a new describe, block,
让我们创建一个新的 "describe" 代码块
ascribe or perform upkeep. This is going to be a regular function.
`describe("performUpkeep")` 然后这里是一个普通函数
And in here, we're going to start and say it can only run if check upkeep is true.
接下来在这里，我们要写 `it("it can only run if checkUpkeep is true")`
(“只有当 checkUpkeep 为 true 时才会运行”)
And this will be an async function.
这里是一个 `async function`
Because we only want to perform keep to work if checkup keep is indeed true.
我们只有在 "checkUpkeep" 确实为 true 时才会想要运行 "performUpkeep"
So we'll say await raffle dot enter. raffle we'll send it some value, raffle entrance fee,
我们写 `await raffle.enterRaffle("value: raffleEntranceFee")`
I'm sorry, there should be curly braces instead.
抱歉，这里应该用花括号替代
And we'll do a weight network dot provider that send EVM increase time inter vol.to number plus one
接下来是 `await network.provider.send("evm_increaseTime", [interval.toNumber() + 1])`
await network dot provider that send UVM mine an empty array there to
`await network.provider.send("evm_mine", [])`
the reason that we're moving time forward and moving our block forward,
我们推动时间和区块的原因当然和上面一样的
of course is gonna be the same thing as above, we want our check upkeep to return true.
我们希望 "checkUpkeep" 能够返回 true
And then we're gonna say const X or transaction equals await raffel dot perform upkeep.
接下来我们要写 `const tx = await raffle.performUpkeep()`
We can either do a blank array, or we could do 0x Doesn't matter.
我们可以放一个空数组，或是使用 `"0x"`，这都是可以的
And we can assert the X.
现在我们可以执行 `assert(tx)`
Now if TX doesn't work, or this error is out or something, this will fail.
如果 "tx" 不起作用，或是发生了报错之类的其他问题，这里就会失败
Right. So that's how we know that this actually can work.
这就是我们判断它是否运行正常的方式
So let's test this out. We want this only to work if checkup keep is true.
让我们来测试一下，我们希望只有当 "checkUpkeep" 为 true 时这些才会被执行
And we made checkup keep true by all the stuff that we did above.
而我们通过上面所做的操作使 "checkUpkeep" 保持为 true
So now we'll do yarn hardhat test dash dash grep with our IT block here.
现在我们来执行 `hh test --grep` 后面是我们 "it" 里的内容
And I spelled perform upkeep wrong perform upkeep.
"performUpkeep" 拼错了，应该是 `performUpkeep`
Let's try spelling things correctly. And let's run that test again.
现在拼对了，我们来再试一次
And great. That's working. I will What else do we want to do?
很好，一切正常，我们还需要做些什么
We want it to revert with raffel. upkeep not needed if checkup keep is false.
我们还要在 "checkUpkeep" 为 false 时使用 "Raffle__UpkeepNotNeeded" 进行回滚
So in here we're gonna say it reverts. When check up keep is false.
所以我们在这里写 `it("reverts when checkUpkeep is false")`
This will be an async function.
这里也是 `async function`
And we're going to do that same syntax await expect raffle dot perform upkeep empty bytes object
接下来就是相同的语法 `await expect(raffle.performUpkeep())` 一个空字节对象
that to.be reverted with.
`.to.be.revertedWith()`
And what do we want it to be reverted with?
我们要用什么进行 "revertedWith" 呢？
Or hoping it's reverted with this with that,
我们要用这个进行回滚
we can run this test here Hardhead test dash dash grep paste that in. And we see that is indeed passing
我们运行 `hh test --grep` 粘贴进去，然后我们看到它确实通过了
now something that you'll notice here is that our
revert actually goes ahead and reverts with all this extra
stuff as well. Our test is smart enough to know that if all we do
is put the name of the error that is getting reverted with
then it's good enough. If we want to be super specific, we
can actually go ahead and make this a string interpolation and
add all of these in here. So we can add the balance that we
expect we can add the players that we expect. And we can add
the raffle statement for now we're just going to keep it as
we're expecting this but if you want to be super specific you
can have your tests expect for exactly the specific values that
you're looking for. But alright, what is the last thing we should
expect form? Well, we should check to see that this actually
gets called the raffle state gets changed. And we admit this
event. So let's go ahead and add that. We'll say it updates the
raffle state admits an event and calls the VRF coordinator to be
an async function as well. Let's do this. So let's go ahead and
let's make checkup keep true, I'm just going to copy paste
these first three lines, since it's going to be exactly the
same. We're going to enter the raffle we're going to increase
the time we're going to mind a new block, then we're going to
call perform upkeep. So we're going to say const, TX response
equals await raffle dot perform upkeep with an empty bytes
object, and we're going to do const TX receipt equals await TX
response dot wait for one block. From this receipt, we're gonna
get the request ID, we're gonna say const Request ID equals, we
can get the request ID. From this omitted event. However, we
should look at our VRF coordinator mock again, when we
call request random words, both in the mock and then in the
actual contract, you'll notice that it also emits an event with
random words requested. And if you look in here, the second
parameter that it has is indeed the request ID. So in reality,
US omitting the request ID is redundant, we can just use the
admitted Request ID from the VRF coordinator for the purpose of
this course and showing you what an event looks like. We're going
to leave it in there. But if you want to go back and refactor
this, you would definitely want to remove this omit. But for
this test, let's do TX receipt dot events. And this is going to
be the first event instead of the zero with event because
before this event gets emitted, this function is going to emit
an event. So instead of the zero with event, this is the first
event that gets emitted after this one. So tax receipts dot
events of one dot args dot request, ID, and then we're
gonna say cert request id.to number is greater than zero. And
then we'll also assert that the
raffle state equals equals one. So we're gonna do const, raffle
state equals await, raffle dot get raffle state. And this
should actually be raffle state.to Number, or to string
and then you know, do whatever we want to do. And this is a
very big it, but we're going to copy the whole thing anyways. HH
test, dash dash grep, paste that in there, we run it, excuse
me.to string equals equals one, transformer time and perfect, we
are passing Great, now it's time for fulfill random words. And
this is where we're going to learn a lot of fantastic stuff
here. So we're gonna make a new describe block zoomed out a
little bit here. And this is going to be our fulfill random
words. It's going to be a function, of course. And in
here, we're actually going to add another before each want to
have somebody have entered the raffle before we run any tests
in here. So we're going to do a before each, which will be an
async. function. And we're just going to run await, raffle that
enter raffle with a value of raffle entrance fee. And then
we're going to do a wait network dot provider dot send EVM
increase time of interval, that to number plus one, and then a
wait network dot provider dot send EVM mine. Comma. Before
we've tried to do any testing of or fulfilled random words, we're
gonna have somebody enter the lottery. And we're going to have
increased the time and mined a new block. Okay, cool. So the
first thing we want to do is want to see that fulfill random
words can only be called so long as there's a request in flight,
so long as there's a requested as long as request random words
has been called. So we can actually check that by running
it can only be called after perform. This will be an async
function. And in here, we're going to revert on some requests
that don't exist. So we'll do await, expect the RF core didn't
a tour be to mock dot fulfill random words. And if we look at
our V RF, coordinator v2 Mark in here has the fulfill random
words function, which is what the chain link node actually
calls and inside Add this function in the actual contract
calls another contract that does the random number verification.
So we're basically checking this part right here. If the request
doesn't exist, we're going to get this non existent request
here. And as you can see, it needs a request ID and a
consumer address. So we're going to guess zero. And the consumer
addresses, of course, it's gonna be raffled out at address, we're
going to expect this to be reverted, with non existent
request. And then we're going to do this exact same thing with a
different Request ID or request ID one. And hopefully, we're
also going to get non existent requests. Now ideally, no
request here would ever allow this fulfill random words to go
through. Now, it obviously would be really hard for us to test
every single possible Request ID, we're going to see a way in
the future to actually test for a ton of these variables with
something called fuzz testing. But we'll get to that in the
future. And I spelt the scribe wrong, let's let's actually
spelled the scribe correctly, go ahead and run this hh test dash
dash grep.
And great it passed.